Matthew Lowery

St. Louis, MO (636) 226-5045 matthewdlowery@msn.com

Summary of Qualifications

Experienced Graphic/Interactive Designer, with 10+ years of professional experience in web and print design, HTML and CSS coding, UI (user interface) design, design and development of WordPress websites. I have continuously shown ability to turn in quality, high-end work that has met the assigned deadline. Practical solution-oriented creative professional who effectively achieves positive bottom line results within budgeted time frames. Focused on Human Centered Design with great communication skills.

Applications

Adobe Creative Suite, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, After Effects, Premiere, Dreamweaver, Flash, WordPress, Microsoft Office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel)

Skills

Print Design, Website Design/Development, Branding, Black and White Photography Development and Print, Email Campaigns, SEO, Online Marketing, User Interface Design, Video Editing, Animation, HTML5 Animation

Experience with Integrating

JavaScript, jQuery, Action Script, PHP Development, Agile and React JS (mostly designing basic website components, i.e. image galleries, video players, ecommerce platforms, etc.)

Portfolio

http://www.behance.net/mattsmadhouse/

Some of the projects include:

- WordPress websites designed/developed for clients including City of Clarkson Valley, Gateway Engraving, and Johnson Group
- Window graphics designed for Premier Dental Group in downtown St. Louis
- Motion graphics showcasing Tri-Leaf Designs previous work synched to royalty-free music as chosen by supervisor

Professional Experience

- **Web Developer** (Entertainment Cruise Productions 01/2024-present)
 - Full-Time role
 - Updated and maintained current cruise sites
 - Worked on building new pages and functions for cruise sites
 - Monitored site performance
 - Collaborated with third-party to better implement new functionality
 - Utilized VSCode, Github, PHP, JQuery, JavaScript, and PHP
 - Worked alongside company's marketing team

• Guest Service Associate (GameStop 10/2023-12/2023)

- Part-time role
- Operated cash register, processed orders, and handled transactions
- Interacted one-on-one with customers, offered recommendations, and answered any questions to the best of my ability
- Restocked and managed in-store inventory
- Monitored and maintained storefront

• Web Developer/Graphic Designer (Natoli Engineering 05/2023-08/2023)

- Originally hired as a contractor
- Utilized expertise in HTML, CSS, PHP, WordPress, Photoshop, Acrobat, Illustrator, InDesign, Premiere, and Microsoft Office
- Updated and maintained websites made for Natoli Engineering and Natoli Scientific in WordPress
- Worked on graphic design projects for upcoming promotions, include web/email banners, post cards, newsletters, and flyers
- Actively looked for opportunities to improve website performance through daily speed tests and side audits
- Assisted with other technology-related issues, such as editing PDF and Word documents, as well as putting together videos using Adobe Premiere
- Worked one-on-one with the marketing team as well as the web host, 1905 New Media, on how to implement certain features into the website and establish best practices

• Web Development Specialist (St. Andrew's Resources for Senior Systems 02/2019-03/2023)

- Utilized expertise in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, WordPress, Adobe Photoshop, Acrobat, Illustrator, Premiere, and Microsoft Office
- Updated and maintained websites made for senior communities owned and operated by St. Andrew's built using hard coding with some work in WordPress
- Worked to increase SEO Optimization through Google Analytics, Google Ads, Google My Business, and Social Media
- Ran monthly website backups and web reports showing success of Google Ads and Analytics for each community, as well as leads generated through CRM
- Assisted with other technology-related issues, such as editing PDF documents and Excel spreadsheets, as well as putting together videos using Adobe Premiere
- Worked one-on-one with staff of each community to improve their web presence

• **WordPress Developer** (The Miller Group 02/2018-01/2019)

- Utilized expertise in WordPress, Adobe Photoshop, Acrobat, Dreamweaver, and Microsoft Office
- Designed and developed WordPress websites for various clients in the St. Louis and Illinois areas, as well as in other parts of the country
- Some clients include Zion Lutheran School, Family Care Health Center, City of Clarkson Valley, Johnson Group, and Gateway Engraving
- Continually maintained and updated websites to ensure functionality
- Looked for ways to improve website performance
- Interacted one-on-one with clients to get feedback on site as well as assist them with any site-related issues

• Graphic Designer/Sign Maker (Topaz SIGNWorks 01/2017-02/2018)

Utilized expertise in Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, & Acrobat, and Microsoft Office

- Designed interior and exterior signs for various clients in the St. Charles area and other parts of the country
- Put together submittals in Microsoft Excel to deliver to clients to show design concepts
- Performed physical labor in installing signs and packing materials for installs
- Operated large format printer for printing larger projects either on regular paper or vinyl
- Internship/Contract-to-Hire (Mascot Agency 06/2013-10/2016)
 - Utilized expertise in Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects, Dreamweaver, Flash animation, and Web Design with an emphasis on HTML, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript, Agile and React JS, and PHP Development
 - Worked on graphic design projects, website updates, data entry, etc.
 - Designed logos, websites, other marketing materials for various start-up companies and law firms in the St. Louis area, including SRNM, Midwest Litigation Services, Gundaker Construction, Club Fitness, Premier Dental, and Dapper Gents Grooming
 - Gained valuable experience in working directly with the clients, working with a team of likeminded designers to accomplish the same goal, and learning the ins and outs of working at a professional design agency

Education

MARYVILLE UNIVERSITY – St. Louis, MO

BA - Interactive Design -Graduated May 2013

CBC HIGH SCHOOL – St. Louis, MO 4 year Honor Student-May 2009

References available upon request